Guide to the Edwin Arlington Robinson Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Edwin Arlington Robinson collection
1897-1941
YCAL MSS 883
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
1.25
(3 boxes) + 1 broadside
Robinson, Edwin Arlington, 1869-1935
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired from various sources. Source information is recorded in the finding aid, and source information from catalog cards has been photocopied and included in the relevant folders. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Edwin Arlington Robinson (1869-1935)
Edwin Arlington Robinson (1869-1935), American poet; his books of poetry include The Torrent and the Night Before (Cambridge, Massachusetts: The Riverside Press, 1896), Children of the Night (Boston: Richard G. Badger & Company, 1897), and The Town Down the River (New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1910).
Arrangement
The manuscript material in this collection was previously cataloged, and the order of the collection by these manuscript catalog numbers has been maintained. The prior manuscript catalog numbers are recorded on the folders.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence and writings documenting the work of Edwin Arlington Robinson. Includes manuscripts, typescripts, and proofs of Robinson's poetry; correspondence with Lawrence W. Lamm, Lucius Beebe, Elizabeth Sparhawk-Jones, and other correspondents; and the typescript of and correspondence pertaining to C. Beecher Hogan's A Bibliography of Edwin Arlington Robinson.
American poetry -- 20th Century; Poets -- United States; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Photographic prints -- United States -- 19th century; Poets -- United States -- 20th Century; Beebe, Lucius, 1902-1966; Hogan, Charles Beecher, 1906-; Lamm, Lawrence W.; Robinson, Edwin Arlington, 1869-1935; Sparhawk-Jones, Elizabeth, 1885-1968
- Nicodemus, page proofs, 1931-1931 (Box 1)
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of Charles Beecher Hogan, December 1941.
- Selection from Bradley Fisk's Bibliography, with Robinson's manuscript notes, 1928-1928 (Box 1)
  Gift of Lucius Beebe, July 1942.
- Two autograph notes, signed, from Robinson to Mrs. A. T. Aldis, 1922-1922 (Box 1)
  Gift of Mrs. Arthur T. Aldis, October 1934.
- Autograph notes, signed, from Robinson to James S. Barstow, Anna Hempstead Branch, "Mr. Appelfeld," Edward Bliss Reed, and Louis Barcroft Runk, 1919-1933 (Box 1)
  Gift of James S. Barstow, 1939; purchased on the George B. Alvord Fund, 1941; gift of Ralph D. Allan, 1951; gift of Edward Bliss Reed, 1936; and gift of Louis Barcroft Runk, 1938.
- 54 autograph letters, signed, and four telegrams to Lawrence W. Lamm, with typed transcriptions and carbon copies of Lamm's letters to Robinson, 1930-1932 (Box 1)
  Source unknown.
- Typescript letter, signed, from Kermit Roosevelt to Lucius Beebe regarding Robinson's poetry, 1930-1930 (Box 1)
- The Man Who Died Twice galley proofs, corrected, 1924-1924 (Box 1)
  Gift of Lucius Beebe, 1942.
- Merlin galley proofs, signed from Robinson to Lucius Beebe, 1929-1929 (Box 1)
- Fortunatus, manuscript poem, undated (Box 1)
- Autograph letters, signed, to Elizabeth Sparhawk-Jones, 1923-1934 (Box 2)
  Gift of Elizabeth Sparhawk-Jones.
- Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas S. Shaw, 1933-1933 (Box 2)
  Gift of Thomas S. Shaw, 1951.
- Two autograph letters, signed, to Marian King, 1927-1927 (Box 2)
  Gift of Marian King, 1958.
- The Children of the Night Library of Congress copyright certificate, 1897-1897 (Box 2)
  Gift of Charles Beecher Hogan, 1951.
- The Silence, manuscript poem, 1918-1918 (Box 2)
- A Bibliography of Edwin Arlington Robinson by C. Beecher Hogan typescript, corrected, 1936-1936 (Box 2)
- Letters concerning C. Beecher Hogan's A Bibliography of Edwin Arlington Robinson, 1936-1936 (Box 2)
  Gift of Charles Beecher Hogan.
- Typescript poems, including Another Dark Lady, The Clinging Vine, Eros Turranos, The Gift of God, Nimmo's Eyes, Old King Cole, The Unforgiven, Variations of Greek Themes, and The Voice of Age, undated (Box 2)
- New York Herald Tribune Robinson feature by Lucius Beebe typescript, corrected, undated (Box 2)
- Forty-seven autograph letters, signed, to Lucius Beebe, 1924-1931 (Box 2)
- Autograph letters, signed, to Mrs. Edward Bliss Reed and "Henry", 1916, 1922 (Box 3)
  Gift of Charles J. Rosenbloom; source unknown.
- Autograph letters, signed, removed from books, 1921-1928 (Box 3)
- C. Beecher Hogan correspondence concerning A Bibliography of Edwin Arlington Robinson, 1935-1941; 3 (Box 3)
- Copy of E. A. Robinson's high school graduation photograph, undated (Box 4 (Broadside))